<(比企谷)なぜ 俺は
あんな恥ずかしいことを…>
Why did I do something that embarrassing?
<うわああ～ッ
死にたい 死にたいよお！>
I wanna die! I wanna die!
<明日 学校行きたくないよお！>
I don't wanna go to school tomorrow!
Am I stupid?! Am I stupid?!
<バカじゃねーの バカじゃねーの
バーカ バーカ！>
Stupid! Stupid!
死にたい…
I want to die.
(小町)どしたの
お兄ちゃん
What's with you, Onii-chan?
放っておいてくれ
Leave me alone.
I'm having a little identity crisis right now.
お兄ちゃん 今 ちょっと
ｱｲﾃﾞﾝﾃｨﾃｨｰｸﾗｲｼｽだから…
はあ… あのね
お兄ちゃん
Look, Onii-chan...
アイデンティティー？ はあ？
Identity? What?
The people who yap about identities all the time
往々にして 個性 個性 言ってる
やつにかぎって個性がねえんだ
are usually the ones with no identity.
大体 ちょっとやそっとで
変わるものが個性なわけあるかよ
Like something that changes so easily could really be an "identity," anyway.
小町ちゃん
何 その言葉遣い 乱暴よ
Komachi-chan, why are you talking like that? It's crude.
Also, you're making a weird face.
あと 顔が変だわ
I was imitating you.
お兄ちゃんのマネだよ
似てねえ
That's nothing like me.
何があったかしんないけどさ
Well, I don't know what happened, but...
今さら その ひねくれた性格が
直るわけないじゃん
As if that twisted personality of yours is gonna straighten out now.
You're a scum-niichan, Scum-niichan!
ごみいちゃんだよ ごみいちゃん
But I kinda like you that way.
でも 小町は そういう
お兄ちゃん 結構 好きだよ
あッ 今の小町的に
超ポイント高い！
Oh, I'd give myself a ton of points for that one!
うふッ
Well, thanks for that.
そいつはありがとよ
俺も結構 好きだ
こういう俺
I like me this way, too.
今の八幡的に 超ポイント高い
I'd give myself a ton of points for that one!
何それ
What the heck?
♬～
Hello.
(雪乃)こんにちは
H-Hey.
お おお
はあ…
(雪乃のせきばらい)
S-So...
その…
(せきばらい)
So... About today.
その 今日のことだけれど
Could you tell me when and where the meeting is?
場所と時間を
教えておいてもらえるかしら
O-Oh, yeah...
ああ だな
それ 由比ヶ浜が
来てからでいいか？
Can it wait until Yuigahama gets here?
Good point... There's no reason to say it twice.
そうね 二度手間よね
Yahello!
(結衣)やっはろー！
おお
Hey.
Hello.
こんにちは
えへへ
You're close...
近い
えへへ
Um, Yuigahama-san, could you move away a bit?
あの 由比ヶ浜さん
ちょっと離れてもらえるかしら
あッ… うん そうだよね
Yeah, you're right.
その そういうわけでも…
Uh... I didn't mean...
(せきばらい)
Yahello!
やっはろー！
いろはちゃん よろしくね
We're ready to go, Iroha-chan!
It sounds as though the situation is not good.
状況は あまりよくなさそうね
Yeah, that's right...
(いろは)そうなんですよ～
何だよ
いえ 別に
What?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, yeah, nothing!
あッ うん そうそう 別に
Seminar Hall 1
At any rate, just be ready.
とりあえず 覚悟だけはしとけよ
≪(玉縄)やあ おや そちらは
初めて見るﾆｭｰﾌｪｲｽだね➡
Hi!
Oh, there's a pair of new faces, I haven't seen before. Welcome.
よろしく 僕は海浜総合高校の…
I'm Tamanawa from Kaihin General High School...
It's worse than I expected.
予想以上ね
見ているだけでも いらだつわ
Just watching them irritates me.
Yeah...
だね
So, what should we do?
それで どうしよっか？
I have no idea.
分からん
まあ とりあえず
できることを考えようよ ねッ？
Well, for starters, let's think of something we can do. Okay?
(平塚)課題は
ちゃんとできたようだな
Looks like you've completed your assignment.
現国に課題なんて出てませんよ
We didn't have a modern Japanese assignment...
では 相談とやらを聞こうか
Well, let's hear what you wanted to ask me.
≪(平塚)で まずは
予算というわけか
So you're starting with the budget, huh?
君達は クリスマスの何たるかを
分かっていないようだな
You guys don't seem to know what Christmas is all about.
はい？
どういうものか見せてやろう
Pardon?
I'll show you what it's about.
ジャジャーン！ これだ！
Ta-da! Here it is!
へえ～ どうしたんですか？ これ
４枚も…
Where'd you get those? And four of them...
結婚式の二次会で当ててな
I won them at a wedding after-party.
それも 二回
Twice, no less...
"You can go by yourself twice!"
一人で二回行けるね！
って二回も言われた
They told me that twice...
<ちょっと何てこと言うんですか>
Wait, what is she saying?
If she went there alone four times,
<この人なら
一人で４回行ったあと>
she'd end up enjoying it so much, she'd pay to go a fifth time!
<案外 楽しくなっちゃって 自腹で
５回目も行くに決まってるだろ>
Worst case, I could even get stuck going with her the sixth time!
<へたすると ６回目のときに
俺が一緒に行っちゃうまである>
Seriously, someone please marry her already!
<ホント 誰か早くもらってあげて>
I'll give you these, so go do some research.
(平塚)これをやるから 少し
勉強してきたまえ それに…
It'll also give you a break from—
Wow, we can?!
いいんですか～
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
Why do we have to go now,
when it's so damn crowded?
何で こんなクソ混んでるときに
そうね 私も あまり…
He's right. I also don't really...
Aww, why not? Let's go!
えーッ いいじゃん 行こうよ！
あッ パンさん！
Pan-san!
パンさんの
バンブーファイトあるよ
We can see Pan-san's Bamboo Fight!
いつでも行けるのに わざわざ
混んでいるときを狙う必要は…
We can go anytime.
I don't see the need to go during a busy season...
ほらほら 今だと
ｸﾘｽﾏｽ仕様になってるんじゃない
But it'll be all decorated for Christmas now, won't it?
No.
いいえ 例年
バンブーファイトは通常仕様よ
The Bamboo Fight is part of the park's regular annual operations.
そもそも 世界観のほうが
重要視されているｱﾄﾗｸｼｮﾝだもの
Emphasis is placed on the world depicted by the attraction, not on the season.
詳しいな
You know a lot about it.
このくらい 一般常識の範ちゅうよ
That much qualifies as common knowledge.
行こうよ～
C'mon, let's go!
絶対に嫌
I refuse.
私 ゆきのんと一緒に行きたいな
I really want to go with you, Yukinon.
You know, the way things have been with us lately...
だってさ 最近ずっとアレだったし
せっかくだし…
And we have this chance...
グッズ
えッ？
Merchandise...
グッズならパンさんの
They'll probably have Pan-san merchandise in Christmas versions.
ｸﾘｽﾏｽﾊﾞｰｼﾞｮﾝが出るんじゃねえの？
そういう感じので
小町のｸﾘｽﾏｽﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄ選びたいんだが
I kind of want to get something like that as a Christmas present for Komachi.
あッ いいじゃん それ
みんなで選ぼうよ
That sounds great! Let's all pick something for her!
そういうことなら
まあ しかたないわね
If that's the case, I guess we'll have to go.
うん！
Yeah!
So wait, is it going to be the four of us?
ていうか この４人で
行くんですか？
I have a yearly passport,
私は年間パスポートがあるから
一枚 不要になるわね
so there'll be one ticket leftover.
≪(いろは)じゃあ もう一人
呼んだほうがいいですね
Oh, then we should invite one more!
Who are you planning to invite?
誰 呼ぶ気だ
ヒ･ミ･ツです
That's a secret!
おい
Hey.
(優美子)あれ～ ヒキオいんの？
Huh? Hikio's here?
(戸部)ヒキオとか超ウケるわ～
ヒキタニくんだし
Hikio! That's hilarious! 'Cause he's Hikitani-kun!
<どっちも違うんですけどね>
Those are both wrong, actually.
何で あいつらもいるんだ？
えッ えーっと
Why are they here, too?
Er... Well...
だって いろはちゃんの味方だけ
するってわけにはいかないじゃん
It's not right to just take Iroha-chan's side all the time!
私も板挟みで大変なんだよ～
I've had it rough, being stuck in the middle!
はあ…
Right...
わあ～ッ
ヒッキー おまたせ！
Hikki!
Thanks for waiting!
はあ…
Has her soul been sucked out of her body?
<魂 吸われてんのか こいつ>
(カメラのシャッター音)
(海老名)結衣～ 撮れたよ
あッ ありがとう
Yui, I got it.
Thanks!
由比ヶ浜さん
勝手に撮るなよ
Yuigahama-san...
Don't take pictures without asking.
だって 言ったら二人とも
撮らせてくれないじゃん
But if I'd asked, you'd both have said no.
だからといって 勝手に撮っていい
理由にはならないでしょ
That doesn't mean you can take them without permission.
ごめんね 次は ちゃんと言うから
Sorry. I'll ask next time.
次はないわ
There won't be a next time.
ご ごめんってば
ゆきのん 待ってよ～
I said I'm sorry! Yukinon, wait!
はあ… ここは
クリスマス色があまりないから
There's nothing particularly Christmasy about this ride.
参考にならないんじゃないかしら
I don't see how it'll help us.
What do I do? What am I gonna do?
どうする
どうするよ 俺!?
はーやとくん！ 一緒に乗るべ
Hayato-kun!
Ride with me!
戸部 あんたさあ…
Tobe...
You know...
戸部先輩 邪魔ですよ
Tobe-senpai.
You're interrupting.
いや 俺 これ系 苦手じゃん
No, it's... I don't handle these things well, you know?
(二人)はあ？
ひッ…
What?!
とべっち 大変そうだね
Looks like Tobecchi's having a tough time.
そうだな 助けてやったら？
He sure is. Why don't you help him out?
ふふふ ここは
ヒキタニくんが助けてあげて
You should help him, Hikitani-kun!
｢とべ×はち｣って どう？
How does "Tobe x Hachi" sound?!
やめてくれ
≪(葉山)いいよ➡
Please stop.
Sure.
一緒に乗ろう 戸部
Let's ride it together, Tobe.
≪(戸部)隼人く～ん！
Hayato-kun!
(海老名)あのときさ ごめん
Listen, I'm sorry about what happened before.
ギクシャクしてたのって
そのせいだったりするのかな？
Is that the reason things have been awkward with you guys?
関係ねえよ そっちは？
That had nothing to do with it.
Everything okay with you?
うん おかげさまで
Yeah.
Thanks to you.
あ ありがとうございま…
Thank y—
Hey, are you okay?
つーかさ あんた 大丈夫？
Oh, it's you, Miura-senpai...
ああ 三浦先輩でしたか
You really look pale.
マジ 顔色悪くない？ 水いる？
ありがとうございます
Want some water?
Thank you.
They're all such nice people.
<三浦 いい人だな～>
Yukinon, are you okay?
ゆきのん 大丈夫？
I'm fine.
大丈夫よ 人混みに
あてられているだけだから
It's just because of the crowd...
Let's go.
行きましょうか
うん
Yeah!
Actually, there's nothing Christmasy about this, either...
<つーか ここも
クリスマス色 ゼロなんだが…>
Hurry up, Hikki!
ヒ ヒッキーも早く！
Off you go to the world of Bamboo Fight!
(係員)バンブーファイトの世界に
いってらっしゃーい
おお すげえな
静かに
Wow, this is pretty cool.
Quiet.
We're not allowed to talk among ourselves?
<まさかの私語厳禁
どんだけ集中してんだよ>
How hard is she concentrating?
≪(優美子)パンさんって
目 かわいくなくない？
Pan-san's eyes aren't cute at all, are they?
それより あーし➡
I'd rather look at Merry-chan the Precocious Cat.
おしゃまキャットメリーちゃん
とか見たい
≪(いろは)そーですか？
Really?
I think this is really cute!
これとか 超かわいいですよ
ねッ 葉山先輩
Don't you think, Hayama-senpai?
<一色のアレは パンさん
かわいいって言ってる>
Isshiki's just trying to make herself look cute by saying Pan-san is cute.
<私かわいいアピール
なんだけどな>
えい！
えい！ えい！
C'mon, that's irritating and cute and annoying and embarrassing!
<ええい うっとうしい かわいい
邪魔くさい 恥ずかしい>
What would you like to have, Hikki-kun?
(声音を変えて)ﾋｯｷｰくんが
ほしいものは何かな？
いや 俺は…
Uh, I...
あッ
俺は 別に…
I don't really want anything...
そ そっか…
O-Oh...
ホントに混んでるね
It really is crowded, huh?
よく こんな時期に
来る気になるよな
I can't believe people want to come here during this season.
I'd rather never do it again.
できるなら もう来たくねえな
But... I want to come here again.
でも 私は また来たいな
いつでも来れるだろ 近いんだし
You can come here whenever you want. It's close.
That's not what I meant...
そういうことじゃないんだけど…
《待ってても
どうしようもない人は待たない》
But I won't wait for someone it's pointless to wait for.
《待たないで こっちから行くの》
Instead of waiting, I'll make the first move.
まあ この時期のランドはアレだが
Hey, coming to Land during this season is one thing, but...
隣のわりかし新しいほうは
どうなんだろうな
I wonder what that newer place next to it is like.
あっちは 結構 静か かも…
That one is pretty quiet... I think.
そうか
Yeah?
うん…
まあ そのうちな
Yeah.
Well, then... someday.
Yeah. Someday.
うん そのうちね
さて 選ぶか～
Well, guess I should pick something.
あッ ヒッキー
これ どう？ どう？
Hikki! How about this?
小町さん
どれが気に入りそうかしら？
Which one do you think Komachi-san would like?
<そんなに本気出さなくても
大丈夫だからね>
You really don't have to get that serious about it...
ねえ ゆきのん
何？
Hey, Yukinon!
What?
えい！
There!
ヒッキー 写真撮って 写真
Hikki! Take our picture!
えッ ああ
Huh? S-Sure...
えッ マジ？
Seriously?!
はあ…
大丈夫か？
You okay?
ええ
あッ やばッ
Yes.
Oh, no!
あッ
先行ってろ あとで追いつく
Go on ahead. We'll catch up.
分かった！
Okay!
行くか
そうね
Ready to go?
Yeah.
Yui
Calling
出ねえし ここまできたら
乗ったほうが早そうだな
Yui
Calling
Call Ended
Yui
She's not answering.
Call Ended
Yui
Now that we've come this far, it'll be faster just to ride it.
出口で待ってるかもしれないし
そ そうね
They might be waiting at the exit.
Th-That's true.
もしかして お前
こういうの苦手？
Does this kind of ride bother you?
苦手 というわけでも
ないけれど
It's not that it bothers me, really...
そういうの先に言えよ
Tell me this stuff beforehand.
戻るぞ
Let's head back.
大丈夫よ
いや あんま得意じゃないんだろ
I'm fine.
No, you don't handle these well, right?
大丈夫だと言ってるでしょう
アホか
I told you, I'm fine.
Are you dumb? It's nothing to get stubborn about.
別に 意地張るような
ことでもないだろ
違うの 本当に大丈夫だから
I'm not. I really am fine.
I wasn't very confident about doing this,
あまり自信はなかったのだけれど
由比ヶ浜さんと一緒のときは
大丈夫だったから
but when I rode with Yuigahama-san, it wasn't a problem.
だから 多分
大丈夫よ
So I think... I'll be fine.
まだ落ちないから
バー握ってなくて大丈夫だぞ
It's not gonna drop yet. You don't have to hold the bar.
ええ そうよね
Yeah... You're right.
You really don't handle these things well, do you?
本当に得意じゃなさそうだな
ええ
Well, a long time ago, my sister...
昔 姉さんがちょっとね
It was when we were little.
小さいころのことよ
When we came to places like this, she would always mess with me.
姉さん こういうところに来ると
いつも ちょっかい出してきたの
I think I can picture that.
何か想像つくな
And she really seemed to be enjoying herself.
そのときの姉さんが
また すごく楽しそうでね
She's always like that.
姉さんは いつもそう
Hey, Hikigaya-kun...
ねえ 比企谷くん
うん？
Save me someday, okay?
いつか 私を助けてね
ほれ
ありがとう いくらだった？
Here.
Thanks. How much was it?
It's fine.
いや いい 病人から
金を巻き上げるのは気が引ける
I wouldn't feel right taking money from someone who's sick.
But it doesn't work that way...
そうはいかないわ
救急車は金取らねえだろ
Ambulances don't make you pay, do they?
Emergency rescue personnel receive appropriate pay...
救急隊員だって 正当な報酬を…
前にも こういうことがあったわね
Something like this has happened before, hasn't it?
Has it?
そうだったか？
店員に取ってもらった景品を
The prize that employee got for us.
Oh, yeah, that.
ああ あれな
We ran into my sister after that.
あのあと 姉さんに会って
Everything you said about her was right, even then. You surprised me.
あなた いきなり 姉さんのこと
言い当てるから驚いたわ
It was just what came to mind when I saw her.
見てて何となく思っただけだ
Besides, even when people see through her, she doesn't try to put up a front.
それに あの人 見抜かれても
とりつくろわないしな
That's true.
そうね それも姉さんの
魅力なんだと思う
I think that's one of her strong points.
She's always been loved by many people.
姉さんは 昔から
色んな人に愛されてきた
私は おとなしくて手がかからない
いい子だと言われたけど…
People said I was a good, quiet girl who didn't cause any trouble,
but I know that behind my back,
その裏で 愛想がない
かわいげがない
they also said I was unfriendly and unlikable.
色々 言われていたこと知ってるの
同じこと俺も言われたな
People said the same thing about me.
In your case, wouldn't they say you were impudent, conceited, and a piece of trash?
あなたのそれは
こしゃくとか生意気とか
生ごみとか そういうものでしょ
Hang on. That last one didn't really fit, did it?
ちょっと 最後の何か
違くなかった？
But I didn't know how I was expected to behave.
でも 私は どうふるまえば
いいのか分からなかった
Still thinking you want to be like her?
まだ あの人みたいになりたいと
思ってるのか？
I'm not sure... I don't think that so much right now.
どうかしら
今は あまり思わないけれど
But she does have something that I don't.
ただ 姉さんは
私にないものを持っているから
And you want that?
それがほしいとか？
いいえ
No.
I just ask myself why I don't have it, and disappoint myself.
何で私は それを
持っていないんだろうって
自分に失望するの
The same goes for you.
あなたもそうよ
You have something that I don't.
あなたも
私にないものを持っている
We were never the least bit similar.
ちっとも
似てなんかいなかったのね
Of course we weren't.
そりゃそうだ
I think that's why I wanted something different.
だから 別のものが
ほしかったんだと思う
私にできることが何もない
って気づいてしまったから
I realized that there was nothing I could do,
あなたも姉さんも
持っていないものがほしくなった
so I started to want something you and my sister didn't have.
I thought if I had that, I could be saved.
それがあれば救えると思ったから
Had what?
何をだ？
さあ 何かしら
What, indeed?
Sorry for going ahead without you!
ごめんね 先行っちゃって
It's not a problem.
別に構わないわ
More importantly, did you take pictures of the parade?
それより パレードの写真
撮っといてくれたか？
うん！ パンさんも撮れたよ
Yeah! I got some of Pan-san, too!
ちょっと データを
確認させてもらってもいいかしら
May I check over the data?
Um, if you'd said something, we could have gone there.
<あの 言ってくれれば
そっち行きましたよ>
Huh? Where's Hayato?
あれ～ 隼人は？
優美子 こっち こっち
Hey, Yumiko, over here!
≪(優美子)ちょ 戸部 何…
Wha— Tobe, what are you doing?
It's starting.
始まるわね
Brings back memories, doesn't it?
何か懐かしいね
うわ～ッ
い いろはす？
I-Irohas?
Hey, Irohas!
ちょ いろはす！
And so, Yukinoshita Yukino.
#10    What the Lights in Each of Their Hands Illuminate.
♬～
"Let it be said that of all who give gifts,
these two were the wisest.
Everywhere they are wisest.
They are the magi."
Wait, really?
They should have talked it over more as a couple.
They don't communicate enough. They'll probably break up.
You're pretty ruthless, Rumi-Rumi.
Don't call me Rumi-Rumi. It's creepy.
C-Creepy? I dare you to say that again!
I mean, please say it again.
Creepy.
One more time! No, three more times!
I'm surrounded by idiots.
(留美)贈り物をする
全ての人達の中で
この二人が最も賢かったのです
世界中のどこよりも誰よりも
賢者の贈り物 て ホントに？
夫婦で話しあえばいいのに
この二人
ｺﾐｭﾆｹｰｼｮﾝ不足で別れそう
留美留美 容赦ねえな
その留美留美っていうのキモい
キ キモ!?
もういっぺん言ってみろ
いや 言ってください
キモい
もう一回 いや あと三回
はあ バカばーっか